<?xml version="1.0"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en"><Esri><CreaDate>20200827</CreaDate><CreaTime>10550100</CreaTime><ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat><ArcGISstyle>ISO 19139 Metadata Implementation Specification</ArcGISstyle><SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce><ModDate>20210413</ModDate><ModTime>161204</ModTime><scaleRange><minScale>150000000</minScale><maxScale>5000</maxScale></scaleRange><ArcGISProfile>ISO19139</ArcGISProfile></Esri><toolbox name="EEMS3.1.0" alias="EEMS3.1.0"><arcToolboxHelpPath>c:\program files (x86)\arcgis\desktop10.6\Help\gp</arcToolboxHelpPath><toolsets/></toolbox><dataIdInfo><idCitation><resTitle>EEMS3.1.0</resTitle></idCitation><idAbs>&lt;DIV STYLE="text-align:Left;"&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;DIV&gt;&lt;P&gt;&lt;SPAN&gt;The Environmental Evaluation Modeling System (EEMS) is a fuzzy logic modeling system. &lt;/SPAN&gt;&lt;/P&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;&lt;/DIV&gt;</idAbs><idCredit>Conservation Biology Institute</idCredit><searchKeys><keyword>fuzzy logic</keyword><keyword>mpilot</keyword><keyword>eems</keyword></searchKeys><idPurp>The Environmental Evaluation Modeling System (EEMS) is an implementation of an evaluative logic modeling system.

Unlike conventional GIS applications that use Boolean logic (True/False or 1/0) or scored input layers, evaluative logic models rely on fuzzy logic. Simply put, fuzzy logic allows the user to assign shades of gray to thoughts and ideas rather than being restricted to black (false) and white (true) determinations. All data inputs (regardless of the type—ordinal, nominal, or continuous) are converted into fuzzy values between -1 (false) and +1 (true) up to six decimal places. A user defined function converts inputs from original values (often referred to as raw values or values in raw space) to fuzzy values (values in fuzzy space). Values in raw space may be combined using mathematical operators (e.g. sum, weighted mean) before being translated into fuzzy space. Values in fuzzy space are combined using fuzzy logic operators (e.g. AND, OR). There are many advantages of this modeling approach: (1) it is highly interactive and flexible; (2) it is easy to visualize thought processes; (3) the logic components are modular making it easy to include or exclude pieces of the logic design; (4) the logic can be managed using a number of different mechanisms; and (5) numerous, diverse topics can be included into a single integrated analysis. Raw, or non-fuzzy, spatial data source inputs (boxes in the example) are populated by one or more GIS data layers (indicated by the stack of gray files). Moving up the diagram, these data are arranged and analyzed to form intermediate map products (purple boxes), which are then arranged and analyzed to generate the final results (green box). One way the user controls the logic of the information is the arrangement of the various data inputs and intermediate products—the higher up in the diagram, the greater the influence on the final result.</idPurp></dataIdInfo><distInfo><distributor><distorFormat><formatName>ArcToolbox Toolbox</formatName></distorFormat></distributor></distInfo><mdHrLv><ScopeCd value="005"/></mdHrLv></metadata>
